Guide to the Valerie Taylor papers, 1913-1997
Taylor, Valerie papers, 1913-1997
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Valerie Taylor from the 1950s to the 1990s, 1950-1997
    - With Cara Vaughn, Bonnie Folse, and Yolanda Berry, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - On television, three photographs, 1983. Phil Donahue show [?] (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - At Himmel Park on Tucson Boulevard, during her son Jim's visit from Los Angeles, between 1983 and 1986. Five photographs taken by Sharon Briekly (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - With Dimitris Stevis, December 7, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - In yard, one photograph, ca. mid-1980s (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - At home with son Jim, two photographs, ca. 1982-1983 and 1988-1990 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - With cane in park, one photograph, ca. late 1980s (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - At mountain, ca. late 1980s (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - At Bentley's, Tucson, AZ, poetry reading, ca. 1987 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - As Tammy Faye Bakker at Halloween party, Tucson, AZ, three photographs, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Valerie Taylor's 75th birthday party, organized by friend Miriam Barsk, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Holding Rice and Beans, ca. 1989 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - In purple dress, with walker, and with friends Miriam Barsk, Winifred Hall, and Roberta Streicher, in Tucson, AZ, three photographs, ca. mid-1990s (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - At a party and at home, three photographs, late 1990s (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - With Miriam Barsk on front porch of Quaker Meeting building, Tucson, AZ, ca. mid-1990s, and Miriam Barsk in 1986, three photographs (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Tee Corinne photos of Valerie Taylor
    - Taken in Margaretvielle, NY, in 1977. Contact sheets, cards produced from the photos, and several prints. Includes a photographs of Tee Corinne taken by Lee Lynch. Thirty-five prints. (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
  - Photographs of family members
    - Sons Marshall, Jerry, and Jim Tate, and their families, ca. 1940s to 1980s; Includes photographs of Marshall with second and third wives and children, and of Jerry and Jim in young age. Also Elsie Young. Includes notes by Tee Corinne on envelope. ca. 40 photographs (Box 35, Folder 1-25)
    - Elsie Young (Valerie Taylor's mother), ca. 1880s to 1920s; As a young woman; with husband and children. Includes Elsie's scrapbook and photos of other family members. Evelen photographs. (Box 36, Folder 1-11)
    - Rose Marie (Valerie Taylor's sister), ca. 1920s to 1960s; As a young woman, with husband and child. ca. 60 photographs (Box 36, Folder 1-11)
    - Marshall Young (Valerie Taylor's father), ca. 1940s to 1980s; As a young man; with wife Elsie Collins (Valerie Taylor's mother) and their; and with second wife Jerri and their children children Bonni, Bud, and Mashallyn. Includes photographs of other children and a letter from Bonni to her parents, Sept. 30, 1968. Some of Marshallyn's photos carry a dedication to Taylor. Also includes Marshall's and Jerri's family correspondence and notes by Tee Corinne. ca. 80 photographs. (Box 37, Folder 1-27)
    - Friends, Includes photograph of Pearl Hart with Jim Osgood and Bill Kelly [?], n.d., and Chicago Tribune photo of Pearl Hart, which Valerie Taylor used to keep on a shelf over her bed (Box 38, Folder 1-17)
    - Unidentified, Tenerife, Canary Islands [?], four photographs, includes note by James Tate (Box 39, Folder 1-13)
- Series IX. Memorabilia, 1975-1992
  - Paul R. Goldman Award, April 12, 1975 (plaque) (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Gay and Lesbian Hall of Fame 1992 (paperweight) (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - (Mounted poems by Will Inman, 1985) (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - (Mounted poems by Will Inman, 1985 and 1986) (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Series X. Audio and Video Tapes
  - Valerie Taylor's words on tape; unidentified circumstances; one audio cassette tape, n.d.; tr7728a
  - Arizona Gay Show # 10: "Growing Old and Gay: An Interview with Valerie Taylor" plus "Best of Arizona Gay", V-387
  - Helen Walters to Valerie Taylor, letter on tape; one audio cassette tape, ca. early 1980?; tr7729a
  - "Our Lesbian Roots" eights lectures delivered by Valerie Taylor at Casa Nuestra in Tucson, AZ; four reel-to-reel tapes, January and February 1980; tr7724-tr7727
  - Edward Mead to Valerie Taylor, letter on tape; one audio cassette tape, June 14, 1981; tr7755a
  - Phil Donahue television show with Valerie Taylor, Del Martin, Joe Norton, and Fred Monroe; one video cassette tape, ca. 1982; V-388
  - Poetry workshop at Flower Square retirement home. Four audio cassette tapes., ca. 1984 or 1985; tr7730a-tr7733a
  - Carey Catherine to Valerie Taylor, letters on audio cassette tapes; six tapes, ca. mid-Eighties; tr7734a-tr7739a